让我们回顾一下前面的mystring示例。
Let's revisit the mystring example from earlier.
使用接口而不是ADT的类，
Using an interface instead of a class for the ADT,
我们可以支持多种实现。
we can support multiple implementations.
所以我们将它声明为公共接口。
So we'll declare it public interface.
我们暂时跳过创建操作，
We'll skip the creator operation for now,
但我们会做另外三个手术。
but we'll have the other three operations.
它们只是没有消息方法体的规范。
And they will just be specs with no message method body.
我们马上会回到方法的静态值。
We'll come back to the static value of method in a minute.
相反，让我们继续使用不同的技术
Instead, let's go ahead and use a different technique
从我们的Java ADT概念工具箱中。
from our toolbox of ADT concepts in Java.
让我们使用构造器来完成这个creator操作。
Let's use constructors for that creator operation.
这是我们的第一个实现。
Here's our first implementation.
这是一个实现mystring的类simple mystring。
It's a class simple mystring that implements mystring.
这就是接口的来源。
So this is where the interface comes in.
它有一个代表。
And it has a rep.
它实现了每个操作——长度，字符，
And it implements each of the operations-- length, charAt,
和子串。
and substring.
我们用@Override来表示
And we're using @Override here to indicate
我们的意思是凌驾于我们从mystring得到的东西之上。
that we mean to override what we got from mystring.
它也有创造者。
And it also has a creator.
这就是我们现在要做的——实现造物主。
And that's where we're at now-- implementing the creator.
下面是我们讨论的优化实现
Here's the optimized implementation we talked about
在前面的阅读中。
in the earlier reading.
这是一个不同的类，快速mystring。
This is a different class, fast mystring.
它仍然实现mystring。
It still implements mystring.
所以它是相同抽象数据类型的实现，
So it's an implementation of the same abstract data type,
但它有不同的代表。
but it has a different rep.
它以不同的方式实现这些操作符。
And it implements these operators in a different way.
所以将这些类与实现进行比较
So compare these classes to the implementations
我们在抽象数据类型中看到的mystring。
of mystring that we saw in abstract data type.
注意之前出现的代码
Notice that the code that previously appeared
在方法的静态值中
in the static value of methods now
出现在这些构造函数中
appears in these constructors, slightly
改成他们指的是这个代表。
changed so that they refer to the rep of this.
还要注意@Override的使用。
Also notice the use of @Override.
此注释通知编译器
This annotation informs the compiler
方法必须与
that the method must have the same signature as one
我们正在实现的接口中的方法。
of the methods in the interface we're implementing.
但是因为编译器已经检查了
But since the compiler already checks
我们已经实现了所有的接口方法，
that we've implemented all the interface methods,
实际上@Override的主要值
really the primary value of @Override
这是一个人类程序员阅读代码。
here is for a human programmer reading the code.
它告诉我们要寻找那个方法的规格
It tells us to look for the spec of that method
在界面上。
in the interface.
如果我们在这里重复这个规格，就不会干了。
If we repeated the spec here, it wouldn't be dry.
别再重复了。
It wouldn't be don't repeat yourself.
但是什么都不说会使代码更难理解。
But saying nothing at all makes the code harder to understand.
所以这表明读者应该
So this signals that the reader should
去看看mystring中的子字符串规范。
go and look at the substring spec in mystring.
最后，注意私有的空构造函数
Finally, notice the private empty constructors
我们用来在子串中创建新的实例，
that we're using to make new instances in substring,
尤其是在我们填写他们的代表之前
in particular right here, before we fill in their reps
用数据。
with data.
我们以前不必写这些空构造函数，
We didn't have to write these empty constructors before,
因为Java默认提供了它们。
because Java provided them by default.
添加构造函数以获取布尔值
Adding the constructors to take Boolean
b意味着我们必须明确声明
b means that we have to explicitly declare
另一个。
this other one.
我们想保密因为我们只想用它
And we want to make it private because we only want to use it
在这里的实现中。
inside the implementation here.
既然我们对好广告了如指掌
Now that we know good ADTs scrupulously
保留自己的不变量，这些构造函数什么也不做
preserve their own invariants, these do-nothing constructors
实际上是个坏模式。
are actually a bad pattern.
他们不会给代表赋值。
They don't assign any values to the rep.
他们当然不会建立不变量
They certainly don't establish the invariants that
对全班都很重要。
are important to the class.
我们应该强烈考虑修订这一实施办法。
We should strongly consider revising this implementation.
因为mystring是不可变的，所以起点
Since mystring is immutable, the starting point
将使所有的领域都成为最终的。
would be to make all the fields final.
现在客户将如何使用这个ADT？
Now how will clients use this ADT?
这里有一个例子。
Well here's an example.
他们可能从构建一个新的mystring开始。
They might start out by constructing a new mystring.
当他们这样做的时候，他们必须使用
And when they do this, they have to use
创建者操作之一——简单mystring或fast
one of the creator operations-- either simple mystring or fast
我的字符串。
mystring.
然后，建造了它，他们
And then, having constructed it, they
将它赋给mystring类型的变量。
assign it to a variable of type mystring.
所以我们只是使用抽象数据类型，
So we're just using the abstract data type here,
不使用特定类型。
and not using the specific type.
这和我们说的很相似
This is similar to what we talked about
有数组列表和列表。
with array list and list.
他们可以对它进行操作。
And they can call operations on it.
所以这和密码很相似，
So this is very similar to the code,
再说一遍，我们以前写Java集合类，
again, that we used to write Java collections classes,
有数组列表和列表。
with array list and list.
不幸的是，这个模式打破了抽象的障碍
Unfortunately, this pattern breaks the abstraction barrier
我们努力在抽象类型之间建立
that we worked so hard to build between the abstract type
以及它的具体表现，
and its concrete representations,
因为客户必须知道
because clients must know the name
具体表示类的。
of the concrete representation class.
因为Java中的接口不能包含构造函数，
Because interfaces in Java can't contain constructors,
必须直接调用其中一个具体类
and must directly call one of the concrete classes
构造器，像这样。
constructors, like this.
那个构造函数的规范不会
The spec of that constructor won't
出现在界面本身的任何地方，
appear anywhere in the interface itself,
所以没有静态保证不同的实现
so there's no static guarantee that different implementations
甚至会提供相同的构造函数。
will even provide the same constructors.
幸运的是，Java的最新版本
Fortunately, the latest version of Java
允许接口包含静态方法。
allows interfaces to contain static methods.
所以我们可以实现creator操作
So we can implement the creator operation
作为静态工厂方法的值
value of as a static factory method
在接口mystring中。
in the interface mystring.
现在客户可以使用ADT而不必中断
Now a client can use the ADT without breaking
抽象的障碍。
that abstraction barrier.
他们只会说我的字符串，而不是价值，
They'd simply say mystring, not value of,
你永远也看不到任何快速mystring的出现
and you'd never see any occurrences of fast mystring
在这个代码的任何地方。
anywhere in this code.
这是另一个例子。
Here's another example.
所以Java集合类集是一个很好的例子
So the Java collection class set is a good example
分离接口和实现的思想。
of the idea of separating interface and implementation.
集合是其他类型E的有限元集合的ADT。
Set is an ADT of finite sets of elements of some other type E.
这是set接口的简化版本。
Here's a simplified version of the set interface.
它设置了一个泛型类型的示例--
It sets an example of a generic type--
其规范是占位符类型的类型
a type whose specification is in terms of a placeholder type
待以后填写。
to be filled in later.
因此，不要编写单独的规范和实现
So instead of writing separate specs and implementations
对于一组字符串，一组整数，
for a set of strings, set of integer,
等等，我们设计并实现了一组E，
and so on, we design and implement one set of E,
其中E是类型参数。
where E is the type parameter.
因此我们可以将Java接口与我们的分类相匹配
So we can match Java interfaces with our classification
ADT操作。
of ADT operations.
所以我们从创造者开始。
So we start with the creator.
在我们的版本中，这将被称为make。
And in our version of set, that's going to be called make.
它需要由元素类型参数化
It needs to be parameterized by the type of elements
我们想创建，但它返回一个新的set实例
that we want to make, but it returns a new set instance
最初是空的。
which is initially empty.
所以客户会编写代码
So then clients will write code, sort of
例如，字符串集等于集合点生成。
like, set of string strings equals set dot make.
编译器会理解的，因为
And the compiler will understand, because of where
我们把它分配给，新的集合
we are assigning it to, that the new set has
成为一组字符串对象。
to be a set of string objects.
下面是观察者方法的一个例子。
Here is an example of observer methods.
大小，例如，获取一个集合并返回其大小。
Size, for example, that takes a set and returns its size.
包含在元素中接受集合并返回
Contains that takes a set in an element and returns
是真是假，取决于元素是否在
true or false, depending on whether the element is in that
准备好了。
set.
注意，规范是用
Notice that the specs are written in terms
我们抽象的集合概念。
of our abstract notion of set.
如果我们提到细节那就糟了
It would be bad if we mentioned the details
集合的任何特定实现
of any particular implementation of sets
有特殊的私人领域。
with particular private fields.
这些规范需要应用于集合的任何有效实现
These specs need to apply to any valid implementation of the set
阿德特。
ADT.
变异者的故事基本上是
And the story for mutators is basically
与观察者相同。
the same as for observers.
我们仍然在水平上写规格
We still write specs at the level
我们抽象的集合模型。
of our abstract model of sets.